[ Boy ] What's your name again ? Chrissie.
Where we goin' ? Swimming.
Slow up.
Slow down.
I'm not drunk. Slow down.
Wait! I'm coming. I'm coming.
I'm definitely coming. [ Giggling ]
Whoa ! Hold on.
I can swim.
I just can't walk or undress myself. [ Chuckling ]
Come on in the water !
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Help me !
[ Whispering ] I'm coming. I'm coming.
Oh, my God !
Oh, God !
Oh, God, no ! God, no !
Please help !
[ Radio ] Local fishing reported good...
and many boat rental yards opening early...
to prepare for the annual seasonal rush.
This is W-I-S-S-- [ Groaning ]
[ Man ] How come the sun didn't use to shine in here ?
We bought the house in the fall...
and this is summer.
Somebody feed the dogs, huh ?
Right.
Do you see the kids ?
[ Radio ] ... forecast calls for clear skies and fair weather...
at least through the regatta weekend.
They must be in the backyard.
In Amity you say ''yahd.''
They're in the ''yahd,'' Not too ''farh'' from the ''carh.''
How's that ? Like you're from New York.
Mom, I got cut. I got hit by a vampire.
You guys were playin' on those swings. [ Phone Ringing ]
Those swings are dangerous. Stay off there. Yuk.
[ Dial Tone ] I think you're gonna live. Hello. It's not the biggest thing I've ever seen.
Yeah. Can I go swimmin' ?
Yeah, but let me clean this first.
What do they usually do, wash up or float or what ?
Make sure you don't go past the jetty.
Oh, no, no, no. Keep 'em there. I'll be out...
in about fifteen, twenty minutes, all right ?
Okay. Get a Band-Aid.
[ Man ] Gotta go... missing person.
Season hasn't started. Nobody's even here yet.
Listen, Chief,
be careful, will ya ? In this town ? Hey. Bye, Dad.
Wait. Let me get on.
I want my cup back ! You'll get it.
Wave good-bye. Bye !
For folks at the beaches, we've got some safety tips for you.
The safety council says --
And nobody saw her go into the water ?
Somebody could've. I was sort of passed out.
You mean, she ran out on you ? No, sir.
She must've drowned.
Look, I reported it to you, didn't I ?
You live here ? No, Hartford.
I go to Trinity. My folks live in Greenwich.
Your folks were born here ? Yeah, I'm an islander.
They moved off when my dad retired.
You an islander ? No, New York City.
You here for the summer ?
C'mon.
Hold it.
[ Chief Brody ] Oh, Jesus.
Well, you're up awful early !
Is the chief in there ?
Well, Chief, what have you got on ?
Polly, if this filing system is going to work,
keep outdated stuff off my desk;
just the pending. Yes, Chief.
We've got a bunch of calls about that karate school.
It seems the nine year olds from the school... [ Buzzing ]
are ''karating'' the picket fences.
Chief Brody's office. The medical inspector.
The fire chief wants you to go over the 4th of July --
I want a list of all the water activities...
that the city fathers are planning for today. Right away ?
Hendricks, where do we keep the ''beach closed'' signs ? Chief?
We never had any. No ?
There's a dead truck smack in front of my store.
[ Brody ] Just have him fill out the form.
Just fill it out.
Look what the kids did to my fence. Eight or nine year olds. Hey, glasses, huh ?
Yeah, glasses. Can I call you this afternoon ?
I'll call you in the afternoon, I promise.
[ Whistle ]
This stuff isn't gonna help me in August.
The summer ginks come down here in June.
You haven't got one thing on here I ordered.
Not a beach umbrella, sun lounger, beach balls --
If I can't get service --
Chief !
Chief, Polly sent me to find you... to tell you there's a bunch of boy scouts in Avril Bay...
doin' their mile swim for their merit badges.
I couldn't call them in. There's no phones out there.
Okay, c'mon, get out.
Take this stuff to the office and get to work on those signs. All right.
''Beaches closed, no swimming by order of the Amity P.D.''
Let Polly do the printing. What's the matter with my printing ?
Let Polly do the printing.
Hey, Chief? Chief Brody !
What have you got there ? We had a shark attack at South Beach this morning, Mayor.
Fatal ! I've got to batten down the beach.
Okay, Albert, Come on, you kook.
Keep your arms up.
Don't fight it. Let it carry you.
Charlie, take me out to those kids, will ya ?
Martin ?
You gonna shut down the beaches on your own authority ?
What other authority do I need ?
Technically you need a civic ordinance or resolution.
That's just going by the book.
We're anxious that you're rushing into something serious.
It's your first summer, you know ?
What does that mean ?
I'm only trying to say that Amity is a summer town.
We need summer dollars.
If the people can't swim here, they'll be glad to swim...
at the beaches of Cape Cod, the Hamptons, Long Island.
That doesn't mean we serve them a smorgasbord.
We never had that kind of trouble in these waters.
What else could have done that to that girl ? Boat propeller ?
I think possibly, yes, a boating accident.
That's not what you told me over the phone. I was wrong.
We'll have to amend our reports.
You'll stand by that ? I'll stand by that.
Oh -- Martin... a summer girl
goes swimming, swims out a little far.
She tires, a fishing boat comes along -- It's happened before.
I don't think you appreciate the gut reaction people have to these things.
I appreciate it. I'm just reacting to what I was told.
Martin, it's all psychological.
You yell ''barracuda'' ...
and everybody says, ''Huh ? What ?''
You yell ''shark,''
we've got a panic on our hands on the 4th of July.
Okay, you can take us back now.
I'm gonna get my raft and go back out in the water.
Let me see your fingers.
Alex Kintner, they're beginning to prune.
Just a little longer ?
Just ten more minutes. Thanks.
[ Woman ] All I want to know--
I want to know one, simple thing. When do I get to become an islander ?
Ellen, never !
You're not born here, you're not an islander.
Hey, Marty, I know you got a lot of problems downtown,
but I got problems at the house I wish you could take care of.
I've got cats parking in front of the house --
[ Screaming ]
And that garbage truck next to the office has got to be moved.
I need a red zone. It's a simple thing you could take care of.
Honey, would you come here a minute, please ? Excuse me.
Are you okay ?
Yeah, I'm fine.
If the kids goin' in the water is worrying you --
No, no. They can play out here on the beach.
It's all right. Let them go.
It's cold.
We know all about you, Chief.
You don't go in the water at all, do you ?
That's some bad hat, Harry.
Chief Brody, you are uptight.
C'mon...
that's it.
C'mon. [ Yelling And Laughing ]
# Oh, do you know the muffin man #
# The muffin man The muffin man # Pippet !
Pippet !
Pippet ! C'mon, Pippet !
Pippet!
Did you see that ? Yeah.
[ Yelling ]
Get everybody out ! Get out !
Get them out !
Michael, get out of the water !
[ Man ] Take it easy. It's gonna be all right.
Alex ?
It's gonna be okay, now.
[ Man ] Alex Kintner is the kid who was missing at the beach.
We don't even know that there's a shark around here.
I can't argue with you. I can't talk to you.
I've got to talk to Mrs. Kintner because this is going to turn into a contest.
It's not just the Gazette. She's advertised in out-of-town papers.
People all over New England are gonna know about it.
Let's go to council chambers where we'll have more room.
I'm responsible for public safety.
Then go see that no one gets hurt.
Marty, do something about this. It's a small story.
I'm gonna bury it as deep as I can... in back with the grocery ads.
Right in here, please.
Move on in, please.
Excuse me, please.
Why do you insist on playing the heavy all the time ?
I have a point of view and it speaks for many of the people here.
It's not only me. How do you feel ? I hope they don't close beaches.
Let's have some order.
Let's have order, please.
Any special questions ?
Is that $3000 bounty on the shark in cash or check ? [ Laughing ]
I don't think that's funny at all. I'm sorry.
All right. All right ! That's private business between you fishermen and Mrs. Kintner.
Martin ? Would you, please ? Chief Brody.
I want to tell you what we're planning so far.
What about the beaches ?
We're gonna put on the extra summer deputies as soon as possible.
Then we're gonna try and use shark spotters on the beach.
Are you going to close the beaches ?
Yes, we are.
We're planning to bring in some experts
from the oceanographic institute.
Only 24 hours.
I didn't agree to that.
2 4 hours is like three weeks!
You all know me,
know how I earn a livin'.
I'll catch this bird for you, but it ain't gonna be easy.
Bad fish.
Not like goin' down to the pond and chasin' bluegills or tommy-cods.
This shark, swallow you whole.
A little shakin', a little tenderizin',
down you go.
And we gotta do it quick. Gotta bring back the tourists.
That'll put all your businesses on a payin' basis.
But it's not gonna be pleasant !
I value my neck a lot more than three thousand bucks, Chief.
I'll find him for three,
but I'll catch him and kill him for ten.
You gotta make up your minds.
Gonna stay alive and ante up, or gonna play it cheap ?
Be on welfare the whole winter.
I don't want no volunteers, no mates.
There's too many captains on this island.
$ 1 0,000 for me, by myself.
For that you get the head,
the tail, the whole damn thing.
Thank you very much, Mr. Quint.
We'll take it under advisement.
Mr. Mayor... Chief.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Oh, God ! You scared me.
Oh.
You know, Ellen, people don't even know how old sharks are.
I mean, if they live two, three thousand years. Martin ?
They don't know ! Enough, enough.
You're not gonna be able to sleep tonight.
Here, c'mon. Thanks.
Wanna get drunk and fool around ?
Oh yeah.
Hey, Mikey really loves his present.
Where is he ?
Sitting in it.
Good God !
All right, Michael, out of the boat !
Tied up to the jetty, sittin' in the boat.
Helpin' Michael.
Get out of that boat ! Hi, Dad. Just a little longer, please ?
It's his birthday tomorrow. I don't want him on the ocean.
He's not on the ocean. He's in a boat. He's not gonna go in the water.
I don't think he'll ever go in the water again after what happened yesterday.
All right, now don't say that.
I don't want that to happen, you know that.
But I want him to read the boating regulations, the rules,
before he goes out on his own.
Michael, did you hear your father ?
Out of the water, now ! Now !
I'm tired. Let's stop before someone reports us.
Don't worry. The chief lives on the other side of the island.
Am I comin' in straight ?
Just keep rowin'.
[ Man ] We'd better catch somethin'. This is my wife's holiday roast.
Don't worry about it. $3000 buys an awful lot of roast.
Come and get it !
The tide's takin' it right out.
Can't we go home ?
Hey. Hey, he's takin' it ! He's takin' it ! - He's takin'it. - Hey, go ! Go !
Go, go, go !
Charlie, take my word for it ! Don't look back !
Swim, Charlie, swim ! C'mon, Charlie, swim !
Swim, Charlie, c'mon, to me, boy! C'mon, Charlie, swim to me!
C'mon, keep swimmin'. Keep swimmin'.
C'mon, a little more. Atta boy! Atta boy!
[ Charlie ] I can't get up ! I can't get up !
Give me your hand. C'mon. I can't get up.
Help me !
Help me ! Get your feet outta the water! Get your feet up. Atta boy! Atta boy, Charlie.
Can we go home now ?
[ Hendricks ] Then Denherder and Charlie sat there...
[ Hendricks ] Then Denherder and Charlie sat there... tryin' to catch their breath, figurin' out how to tell Charlie's wife...
what happened to her freezer full of meat.
That's not funny at all !
Mrs. Kintner must have put her ad in Field and Stream.
Looks more like the National Enquirer.
[ Arguing ]
All right, hold it ! Just hold it !
Hello. Hello back, young feller. How are you ?
I hope you're not going out with those nuts, are you ?
The Weetock boat's gotta move out first. You have to move out or he can't get out at all.
Ahoy ! Don't raise sail. You're just gonna luff it.
You got a paddle ? Scull it out of here. Yeah.
Officer, wait a second. Wait. Just--
Hey, how many guys you gonna put aboard that boat ?
Whatever's safe, right ? Well, that ain't safe !
Hey, watch it. That's dynamite.
Wait a minute. Where are you going with that ?
I'm goin' on the boat. Oh, no, no, no.
Help me get those guys out of the boat, will you ?
Sure.
Gentlemen, the officer asked me to tell you...
that you're overloading that boat.
Ah, get out of here. Ah.
You ain't going! What do you care ? Okay.
Can you tell me if there's a restaurant or hotel on the island ?
Yeah, you walk straight ahead.
[ Laughing ] Ha-ha-ha. They're all gonna die.
Polly, listen. We've got roadblock signs outside.
You gotta get somebody to help us.
Get those roadblock signs out on the highway,
because we got more people down here than we can handle.
- Yeah ? - What are you doing ?
These are your people. Go and talk to them. Those aren't my people !
They're from all over. Did you see the license plates ?
Connecticut, Rhode Island, New Jersey.
What happened to the extra help we're supposed to get ?
That's not 'til the 4th of July. Until then, it's you and me.
You know those eight guys on the fantail launch ? Yeah.
None of them are gonna get out of the harbor alive.
That's what I'm talkin' about. You know their first names. Talk to those clowns !
Everyone seems to be having a good time today. Tell me about it !
I'll get back to you. Could you tell me how I could find chief Brody ?
Who are you ? Matt Hooper.
I'm from the oceanographic institute.
Oh, for Christ sakes. You're the guy we called.
I'm Brody. Oh, I'm very glad to meet you.
I'm glad to meet you too. I know you got a lot on your hands now, but --
What can we do for you ?
I think the best thing for me to do...
is to see the remains of the first victim, the girl on the beach. Okay, fine,Just bear with me. Thanks. Sure.
Wait'll we get them silly bastards down in that rock pile.
They'll wish their fathers had never met their mothers...
when they start diggin' their bottoms out and slammin' into them rocks.
[ Man ] Get away from there, you goddamn fool!
What's the matter with you ? You wanna swamp us you crazy son-of-a-bitch ?
What are you doin' ? What are these guys doin' out here ?
What the hell they doin' ?
They're chummin' right now.Chumming ? What the hell is that ?
They're tracking the shark.
$3000 divided four ways is what ?
Let's show Mr. Hooper our accident.
''Victim identified as Christine Watkins, female Caucasian.''
Here's the way we have it.
''Probable boating accident.'' Yeah.
All right ?
The height and weight of the victim...
can only be estimated from the partial remains.
[ Breathing Deeply ]
The torso has been severed in mid-thorax, no major organs remaining.
May I have a glass of water ?
The right arm has been severed above the elbow,
with massive tissue loss in the upper musculature.
Thank you, very much.
Partially denuded bone remaining.
This was no boat accident. Did you notify the Coast Guard about this ?
No, it was only local jurisdiction.
The left arm, head, shoulders, sternum and portions of the rib cage are intact.
Do not smoke in here !
This is what happens.
It indicates the non-frenzied feeding of a large squalus,
possibly Longimanus or Isurus glauca.
Now... the enormous amount of tissue loss...
prevents any detailed analysis.
However, the attacking squalus must be considerably larger...
than any normal squalus found in these waters.
Didn't you get out a boat and check out these waters ? No.
[ Hooper ] This is not a boat accident!
It wasn't any propeller. It wasn't any coral reef.
And it wasn't Jack the Ripper !
It was a shark.
[ Man ] You heard it.
We brought it home!
Listen, I wanna go AP and UPI. I wanna get on the state wire services.
See if Boston'll pick it up.
Call Dave Axelrod. Tell him he owes me a favor.
This is the shot I want with everybody and the fish in it.
[ Reporter ] Can we please get organized?
I wanna get a picture for the paper.
Ben Gardner get this ?
[ Man ] No, no, no. We caught it.
We got it. We got it.
Hey, that's swell. That's a beauty, ain't it ?
[ Reporter ] I need a picture for the paper. Clear out of the way, please.
Just the guys who caught the fish.
Could you open it up a little, please ?
C'mon, guys, please. I need a picture for the paper.
Could we get the ''beach closed'' sign ?
[ Indistinct ]
Young fellow, could you step out of the picture ?
Get real. We're ready.
- Can you get that, please ?
- How's that ?
Larry !
Larry, you won't believe it.
What kind of a shark is it ? I don't know.
I think it's a mako. It's got a deep throat.
- Yeah, but what kind of shark ?
- Tiger shark.
A what ?
We can start breathing again.
Ben getting plenty of pictures ? You bet he is.
What is this ''bite radius'' crap ? That is a big mouth !
Stuff your head in there and find out if it's a man-eater !
All I'm saying is that it may not be the shark.
It's just a slight -- Matt ?
This is Larry Vaughn, our mayor. Hi.
Matt's from the oceanographic institute. Nice to meet you.
Terrific, huh, Mayor ?
Martin, there are all kinds of sharks in the waters;
hammerheads, white tips, blues, makos.
The chances these bozos got the exact shark --
There's no other shark like this in these waters.
It's a hundred to one... a hundred to one.
I'm not saying this is not the shark. It probably is.
It's a man-eater. It's extremely rare for these waters.
But the fact is that the bite radius on this animal...
is different than the wounds on the victim.
I just -- I wanna be sure.
You wanna be sure. We all wanna be sure, okay ? What I want to do is simple.
The digestive system of this animal is very slow.
Whatever it's eaten in the last 24 hours is bound to still be in there.
Then we'll be sure.
It may be the only way to confirm it, huh ?
Look, fellas, let's be reasonable, huh ?
This is not the time or place to perform ...
some kind of half-assed autopsy on a fish.
I'm not going to stand here and see that thing cut open...
and see that Kintner boy spill out all over the dock !
Chief Brody ? Yes ?
I just found out...
that a girl got killed here last week.
And you knew it !
You knew there was a shark out there.
You knew it was dangerous.
But you let people go swimming anyway.
You knew all those things,
but still my boy is dead now.
And there's nothing you can do about it.
My boy is dead.
I wanted you to know that.
I'm sorry, Martin. She's wrong.
No, she's not.
[ Vaughn ] All right, fellas,
let's cut this ugly son-of-a-bitch down... before it stinks up the whole island.
Harve, you and Carl take it out tomorrow and dump it in the drink.
Come here.
Give us a kiss.
Why ?
Because I need it.
Hello. Get out of here.
[ Ellen ] Can I help you ? Mind if I come in ?
I'm Matt Hooper. Hi. Ellen Brody.
Your husband's home ? I'd like to talk to him. Yes.
Yes, so would I.
Come in. Can I get you some coffee ? No, nothing, thank you.
Oh, wine. How nice.
How was your day ?
Swell.
Yeah. I got red and white.
I didn't know what you'd be serving. Oh, that's nice.
Is anyone eating this ?
No.
My husband tells me you're in sharks.
[ Hooper Laughing ] Excuse me, well, yes. I've never heard it quite put that way,
but yes, I am. I love sharks.
You love sharks. Yeah, I love them.
When I was twelve, my father got me this boat
and I went fishing off Cape Cod.
I hooked a scup and as I was reeling it in,
I hooked a 4-and-a-half foot baby thresher shark, who proceeded to eat my boat. [ Laughing ]
He ate my oar, hooks, and my seat cushions.
He turned an inboard into an outboard. Scared me to death.
And I swam back to shore.
When I was on the beach, I turned around...
and actually saw my boat being taken apart.
Ever since then, yes, I have been studying sharks.
That's why I know that I'm going to go to the institute tomorrow...
and tell them that you still have a shark problem here.
Why do you have to tell them that ? Sorry.
I'm sorry. You told me the shark was caught.
I heard it on the news, on the cape station.
They caught a shark, not the shark.
Not the shark that killed Chrissie Watkins;
and probably not the shark that killed the little boy,
which I wanted to prove by cutting the shark open.
You want to let that breath -- ? Nothing.
Yeah, yeah.
You know, uh...
you're gonna be the only rational man left after I leave tomorrow.
Where you going ? Ahh.
I'm going on the Aurora.
What is that ?
It's a floating asylum for shark addicts.
Pure research... 1 8 months at sea.
Martin hates boats.
Martin hates water. Martin --
Martin sits in his car when we go on the ferry to the mainland.
I guess it's a childhood thing.
There's a clinical name for it. Drowning.
Is it true that most people get attacked by sharks...
in 3 feet of water, about 1 0 feet from the beach ?
Yeah.
And before people started to swim for recreation,
I mean, before sharks knew what they were missing,
that a lot of these attacks weren't reported ?
That's right.
Now, this shark that swims alone -- Rogue.
What's it called ? Rogue.
Now this guy, he keeps swimming around in a place...
where the feeding is good until the food supply is gone.
That's called territoriality.
It's a theory that I happen to agree with.
Why don't we have one more drink and go down and cut that shark open ?
Martin ? Can you do that ?
I can do anything. I'm the chief of police.
We start in the alimentary canal...
and open the digestive tract.
Agh ! Just like I thought ! What ?
Came up from the gulf stream,
from southern waters.
He didn't eat a car, did he ? No.
A tiger shark's like a garbage can. It'll eat anything. Somebody probably threw that in the river.
That's it.
I've got to close the beach, call the mayor.
You've got a bigger problem than that, Martin.
You've still got a hell of a fish out there...
with a mouth about this big.
How do we confirm that by morning ?
If he is a rogue and there's any truth to territoriality at all,
we've got a good chance of spotting him between Cape Scott and South Beach.
Where you going ? I'm gonna find him now.
He's a night feeder.On the water ?
We're not gonna find him on land.
I'm not drunk enough to go out on a boat ! Yes, you are.
No, I'm not.
I can't do that ! Yes, you can.
The crime rate in New York will kill you.
There are so many problems, you never feel like you're accomplishing anything.
Violence, rip-offs, muggings.
Kids can't leave the house. You gotta walk 'em to school.
But in Amity, one man can make a difference !
In 25 years, there's never been a shooting or murder.
Martin, want a pretzel ?
Where are we ?
We're right in the stretch where he's been feeding.
Can you get the late show on this thing ?
No, it's a closed-circuit TV system. I have underwater cameras fore-and-aft.
Who pays for all this stuff? The government, an institute ?
This stuff costs a lot of money.
Well, I pay for this mostly myself, actually.
You're kidding.
No.
You rich ? Yeah.
Yeah ? How much ?
Personally or the whole family ?
Doesn't make any sense.
They pay a guy like you to watch sharks ?
Well, uh --
It doesn't make much sense for a guy who hates water to live on an island, either.
It's only an island if you look at it from the water.
That makes a lot of sense.
[ Beeping ] [ Martin ] What is that thing doing ?
It's a fish finder.
It's probably a school of mackerel all clumped together.
Wait a minute.
There's something else out there. What is it ?
About a hundred yards, south southwest.
[ Brody ] That's Ben Gardner's boat ! You know him ?
It's all banged up. Sure, I know him. He's a fisherman.
What happened ?
Martin, I've got to go down and check their hull.
Why don't we tow it all in ? We will.
I've got to check something out. Get the lines for me.
Let's tow it in.
Don't worry. Nothin's gonna happen.
What am I supposed to do while you're gone ?
Nothing...
absolutely nothing.
Don't touch any of the equipment.
I'll be back in two minutes.
This is a great white, a big one !
Any shark expert in the world will tell you it's a killer, a man-eater !
The situation is, that apparently a great white shark...
has staked a claim in the waters off Amity Island.
He's going to continue to feed here as long as there is food in the water.
There's no limit to what he's gonna do.
We've had 3 incidents, two people killed in a week.
It happened before.
The Jersey beach, 1 91 6, Five people chewed up in the surf.
Tell him about the swimmers.
A shark is attracted to the exact kind of splashing that occurs...
whenever human beings go in swimming. You cannot avoid it.
If you open the beaches on the 4th of July,
it's like ringing the dinner bell.
Mr. Vaughn, I pulled a tooth the size of a shot glass...
out of the wrecked hull of a boat out there, the tooth of a great white.
It was Ben Gardner's boat. It was all chewed up.
You should've seen it !
Where is that tooth ? Did you see it, Brody ?
No, he dropped it -- I had an accident.
What did you say the name of this shark is ?
It's a Carcharodon carcharias, a great white.
But you don't have the tooth ?
We depend on the summer people for our very lives.
You're not gonna have a summer unless you deal with this problem.
We're gonna have to hire somebody to kill the shark !
We're gonna have to tell the Coast Guard.
You'll have to contact the shark research panel.
Every nut in the world is gonna come in here !
I don't think either one of you
are familiar with our problems !
I'm familiar with the fact tha
t you are going to ignore this particular problem...
until it swims up and bites you on the ass !
There are two ways to deal with this problem.
You're either gonna kill this animal or cut off its food supply.
We have to close the beaches!
Brody, sick vandalism !
That is a deliberate mutilation of a public service message.
I want those paint-happy bastards caught
and hung up by their Buster Browns !
That's it. I'm not gonna waste my time arguing with a man...
who's lining up to be a hot lunch.
See you later, buddy. Don't do this !
Mr. Vaughn,
what we are dealing with is a perfect engine,
an eating machine. It's a miracle of evolution.
All this machine does is swim, eat,
and make little sharks, and that's all.
Take a long, close look at this sign.
Those proportions are correct.
Love to prove that, wouldn't you ? Get your name into the National Geographic ?
[ Brody ] If we make an effort today, we might be able to save August.
August ?
For Christ sake, tomorrow's the 4th of July !
And we will be open for business,
one of the best summers we've ever had.
If you fellas are concerned about the beaches, do whatever you have to to make them safe.
But those beaches will be open for this weekend.
I wanna know how many men you're gonna send me.
Doctor, there is no need for me to come to Brisbane...
when I have a great white shark right here.
[ Brody ] We need men to patrol the swimming area.
We've gotta have help, anybody with a gun or boat.
Monday !
Is Chief Petty Officer Feldman there ? What ? Dad !
He's the little guy with the crew cut.
Operator, isn't there a phone on the island ?
Could you connect me ?
[ Brody ] I'm over at the beach.
Brody to ''Gotcha. '' Do you read me ?
Those guys from the TV station on the mainland is here.
All right. I'll get to them later.
Brody to ''Scutbucket.'' Please come in.
Brody to ''Daisy.'' Do you read me ?
[ Brody ] ''Fascinatin'Rhythm, '' do you read me ?
Come in, Hooper. What do you see ?
Nothing here, Martin, and nothing on sonar.
Amity Island has long been known for its clean air,
clear water, beautiful white sand beaches.
But in recent days,
a cloud has appeared on the horizon of this beautiful resort community,
a cloud in the shape of a killer shark.
[ Radio ] This stadium does hold the water well... and it is very soggy in the outfield.
Two balls, one strike, runners at first and third. Here's the pitch.
Fly ball, deep left field.
Oh, hi, Larry. Why aren't you in the water ?
Well, I just put some suntan lotion on...
and I'm trying to absorb-- Nobody's going in.
Please, get in the water.
Mike, come here.
Listen, Mike, do me a favor, will ya ?
What ? Take the boat and put it in the pond.
Pond's for old ladies. I know it's for old ladies.
Just do it for the old man, huh ?
Please.
All right.
Thanks.
[ Whispering ] I've got Sean.
Michael... wait ! Michael, wait.
Michael, I don't like you no more.
[ Children ] Hey you! Throw it here! Give it to me!
I can stand Harry. You know, hey there, lover.
Daisy, Daisy, this is Hendricks.
Anything ? Thought I saw a shadow. Over.
[ Radio ] Hendricks, this is Daisy, I don't see anything.
False alarm, must be this glare.
I'm pleased and happy to repeat the news...
that we have caught and killed a large predator... that supposedly injured some bathers.
It's a beautiful day, the beaches are open...
and people are having a wonderful time.
Amity, as you know, means friendship.
My...
God !
Jesus Christ ! Fin ! Shark ! Three-five-zero ! [ Radio ] We've got something here, something big.
Get in there as fast as you can. Red one ! Red one !
[ Radio ] Get your people out. There's a shark in the bay.
- Everybody out of the water! - No whistles ! No whistles !
[ P.A. System ] Everybody, please, get out of the water.
Don't push. Everybody, come out of the water, please.
Move up past the refreshment area !
Move it, please. Let's go.
Past the refreshment area.
Come on, darlin'!
Michael ! Michael !
[ Radio ] What's going on out there ? Give an answer, please.
What's going on out there ?
Come in ! Come in !
He made me do it. He talked me into it !
Please, please, move back. Let's move back, please. Give these people air.
Please, move back. Move back.
[ Hooper ] It's just a hoax.
There are 2 kids with a cardboard fin.
Is everyone there okay ? Did everyone get out all right ?
[ P.A. System ] Folks, we had...
some practical jokers out there with a big fin.
Shark !
The shark !
[ Woman ] It's going into the pond! Shark in the estuary!
Now what ?
Michael's in the pond.
It's going in the pond!
Somebody do something! It's in the pond!
In the pond! The shark!
Hurry up, get that done. Can't do a damn thing--
Get that rope undone. Get that untangled. I'm doing it.
Hey fellas ! Fellas !
Haul in the sheet and make it fast.
[ Woman ] Shark in the pond!
Hey, you guys, you okay over there ?
In the pond !
Get out of the water! Somebody help him !
[ Man ] Somebody get a gun ! Get a gun and shoot it!
Does anybody have a gun ?
Oh, my God ! Michael !
Is he dead ? No, he's not. He's in shock.
[ Ellen ] Michael!
Doctor said he's okay. Mild shock. He can go home in the morning. Thank you.
Hey, how's my big kid ? I'm all right.
You are. You gonna miss me tonight ?
You can watch TV. Want me to bring you anything from home ? My cars. Your cars. What about ice cream ?
Coffee. Coffee.
Want to take him home ?
Like to New York ?
No, home here.
I'm sorry. I'm truly sorry.
Got a pen, Larry ? Pen ?
Yeah, pen, you know.
'Cause you're gonna do what you do best.
You're gonna sign this voucher so I can hire a contractor.
I don't know if I can do that without--
I'm gonna hire Quint to kill the shark.
[ Mumbling ] August. What ?
What are you talking about ? Summer is over.
You're the mayor of Shark City. These people think you want the beaches open.
I was acting in the town's best interest.
You were, and that's why you're gonna do the right thing.
Sign this and pay that guy what he wants. Martin.
Martin.
My kids were on that beach too.
Sign it, Larry.
[ Quint ] $ 1 0,000. $ 200 a day whether I catch him or not.
[ Brody ] You've got it.
Get the mayor off my back so I don't have any more of this zoning crap.
You've got that.
One case of apricot brandy. You buy the lunch.
Two cases. You get dinner when you get back.
[ Quint ] Champagne, pate de foie gras, Iranian caviar...
and don't forget the color TV.
Hey, Chief, try this. Made it myself. Pretty good stuff.
Thanks.
[ Quint ] Here's to swimmin' with bowlegged women.
[ Indistinct Noise ] Excuse me, Chief.
[ Quint ] Can't get a good man these days under 60.
All gone at least 35 years.
Don't drink that. [ Quint Mumbling ]
Mr. Quint ? Mr. Quint ? Mr. Quint, you're gonna need an extra hand.
This is Matt Hooper. I know who he is.
I've crewed three trans-pacs. Transplants ?
He's from the oceanographic institute. An America's Cup trial.
I'm not talkin' about pleasure boatin' or day sailin'.
I'm talkin'about workin' for a livin', sharkin'.
I'm not talking about hooking some dogfish or sand shark.
I'm talking about finding a great white.
Porkers ? Talking about porkers, Mr. Hooper ?
Tie me a sheepshank.
[ Sighing ] I haven't had to pass basic seamanship in a long time.
You didn't say how short you wanted it.
How's that ?
Give me your hands.
Dogfish ?
You got a $5,000 net and $2,000 worth of fish.
Along comes Mr. Whitey. By the time he's finished with that net...
it looks like a kiddie's scissors class cut it up for a paper doll.
You got city hands. You've been countin' money all your life.
All right, all right ! I don't need this ! I don't need this working-class hero crap.
You're not gonna do this aboard the ship, are you ?
Maybe I should go alone.
It's my party. It's my charter.
Yeah, it's your charter. It's my vessel !
When you're on board my vessel, I'm mate, master,
pilot and I'm captain.
Take him for ballast, Chief.
You got him.
Pliers, iron.
[ Hooper ] Sample bottles, dye marker, flares, safety float,
temperature gauge, spear gun, SMG--
What are ya, some kind of half-assed astronaut ?
[ Quint ] Take that stuff below and lash it secure.
Jesus H. Christ.
When I was a boy, every squirt wanted to be... a harpooner or swordfisherman.
What you got here ? A portable shower or monkey cage ?
Anti-shark cage.
You go inside the cage ?
Cage goes in the water ? You go in the water ?
Shark's in the water ? Our shark ?
# Farewell and adieu to you fair Spanish ladies #
# Farewell and adieu you ladies of Spain #
# For we've received orders  #
for to sail back to Boston
And so nevermore shall we see you again
Did you take your Dramamine ? Yes.
I put an extra pair of glasses in your black socks.
There's the stuff for your nose, the zinc oxide, and Blistex is in the kit.
[ Quint ] Son of a bitch !
Goddamn women today can't handle nothin'.
Young girls ain't smart like their grandmothers.
That's got to be Quint. Colorful, isn't he ?
He scares me.
Don't use the fireplace. I haven't fixed the flue yet.
What am I gonna tell the kids ?
Tell 'em I'm going fishing.
[ Quint ] Break it up, will ya, Chief? Daylight's wastin'.
Front, bow. back, stern. Don't get it right, squirt,
I'll throw your ass out the round window on the side!
Come on, Chief, this isn't a picnic.
See ya got your rubbers. [ Laughing ]
Here lies the body of Mary Lee.
Died at the age of 1 03.
For 1 5 years she kept her virginity,
not a bad record for this vicinity.
All right, Commissioner, fasten your safety belts.
If you see a shark, Hooper, swallow.
[ Quint ] Up periscope. Rig for depth charge.
Stand by... fire drill.
You know what I'm talkin'about, Chief? How's the missus, Chief?
If they don't like you goin' out, they'll love you comin' in.
# Oh, yo, ho, ho and a bottle of rum #
# Fifteen men on the dead man's chest #
Keep that chum line goin'. We got five miles on him.
Who's driving this boat ? Nobody, the tide.
One time I got a 1 6-footer off Montauk.
Had to stick two barrels in him to wear him down and bring him up.
Nowadays these kids take out everything.
Radar, sonar,
electric toothbrushes.
Jesus H. Christ.
Hey, Chief, best drop another chum marker.
[ Hooper ] Damn it, Martin !
This is compressed air.
What the hell kind of a knot was that ? You pulled the wrong one !
You screw around with these tanks and they're gonna blow up.
Yeah, real fine, expensive gear you brought out here.
But I don't know what that shark's gonna do with it.
Might eat it, I suppose. Seen one eat a rockin' chair.
Hey, Chiefy, next time,
just ask me which line to pull, right ?
[ Quint ] Little brown eel comes out of the cave,
swims into the hole,
comes out of the hole, goes back to the cave again.
Not too good, is it, Chief?
Well, nothing's easy, is it ? One more time.
[ Brody ] The brown eel comes out of the cave.
Hey ! I got it !
What ? Get behind me !
[ Quint ] Hooper, reverse her!
Takin' a hell of a lot of line !
Chief, get the scoop. Wet the reel !
Hooper, reverse her !
Duck your head down. We're swinging. Get behind me again.
No more water. Don't drown me.
Hooper, you idiot ! Starboard ! Ain't you watchin' it ?
[ Quint ] Hooper, neutral.
Where's he goin' now ?
He ain't foolin' me.
What's he yankin' on now ?
Go on. Try it.
I don't know, Chief. He's very smart or very dumb.
Jesus Chr--
He's gone under. Gone under the boat.
I think he's gone under the boat.
Yeah, it's too easy.
He ain't a smart, big fish. He's gone under the boat.
Keep it steady now. I got somethin' very big.
I don't think so.
Chief, Chief, put your gloves on.
Put your gloves on, both of ya.
Gettin'ready to run out again.
Quint, let it go.
You may be a big yahoo in the lab, but here you're just supercargo.
If you don't want to backstroke home, get down here.
All right, you don't want to listen to me, don't.
It's not a shark.
The wire's showing. The wire's showing ! Unbuckle me.
Get the other side. It's tuna or swordfish.
Wastin' our time.
Okay, take this rod. Give the chief a hand.
Right ! Oh, shit !
It may be a marlin or a stingray,
but it's definitely a game fish. Ohh--
Gamin' fish, eh ? Marlin, stingray ?
Bit through this piano wire ? Don't tell me my business.
Get back on the bridge.
Doesn't prove a thing.
It proves one thing.
It proves you wealthy college boys don't have the education...
to admit when you're wrong.
What's the point ? Hooks and lines ?
Well, you lose one, you rig one.
[ Engine Starting ] Hooper ! Twelve minutes, south southeast, full throttle.
Aye, aye, sir. [ Grumbling ]
See what I do, Chief, is trick 'em to the surface.
I jab at 'em. I'm not gonna haul 'em up like catfish.
Hooper !
Full throttle!
I don't have to take this abuse much longer.
Your head's bleedin'. First aid there.
Brody, start that chum line again, will ya ?
Let Hooper take a turn.
Hooper drives the boat.
Stop playin' with yourself. Slow ahead, if you please.
Ya heard him. Slow ahead.
Slow ahead.
I can go slow ahead. Come on down and chum some of this shit.
You're gonna need a bigger boat.
Shut off that engine !
- That's a twenty-footer. - Twenty-five.
Three tons of him.
We're gonna need a bigger boat, right ?
Gotta get to work. How do we handle this ?
[ Hooper ] Come front. I need you.
[ Hooper ] He's circling the boat.
Come on, Martin.
[ Radio ] Amity light station to Orca. This is Amity light station to Orca. Come in, Orca.
Orca. Come in.
I have Mrs. Martin Brody here. Put her on.
[ Hooper ] Go on, Martin, move, move! I'm not going out there!
Beyond the barrels, go to the end of the barrels.
Further out ! What ?
Go further out ! What for ?
Will you go to the end of the pulpit, please ? What ?
What for ? I need something in the foreground to give it scale.
Foreground, my ass !
Your husband's all right. He's fishing. Just caught a couple of stripers.
We're bringin' dinner. We haven't seen anything. Over. Out.
I'm not staying here. I'm begging you.
Martin, goddamn it ! Come here, darlin', come here !
[ Hooper ] Beautiful!
Chief, get on the bridge. Take her forward, steady.
I've never steered a boat in my life.
Watch my hand. Take her steady.
Mr. Hooper, attach the end of this line to the first keg.
I've got to get a good shot at that porker's head.
Comin',
comin'.
Hooper, get clear of the barrel.
Hooper !
Tie it up, will ya ? Your turn, Quint.
Hooper, where are ya ?
Hooper, hurry it up now. Tie it on.
Hurry up, he's comin' straight for us. Don't screw it up. Don't wait for me !
Come on, Hooper,
Hurry up ! Tie it on !
Now. Now.
[ Brody ] Kill him, Quint. Kill him !
Now !
- Shoot ! - [ Gunshot ]
Time !
[ Quint ] What were you doin' ? I didn't get a clean shot in the head.
All right, let's see how long that barrel takes to bring him up.
Free another barrel. I'm coming around again.
What do we do now ? We're quitting, right ?
[ Quint ] We've got one barrel on him. We stay until we find him again.
We could radio in and get a bigger boat--
Chief.
Don't you worry about it, Chief.
It won't be permanent.
Want to see something permanent, boom, boom, boom ?
Hey, Hoop,
you wanna feel something permanent ?
Just put your hand underneath my cap. Feel that little lump ?
Knocko Nolans, St. Paddy's Day, Boston.
I got that beat.
That's a moray eel.
Bit right through my wet suit.
Hoop, now, listen, I don't know about that,
but I entered an arm wrestling contest...
in an Okie bar in San Francisco.
I can't extend that, you know why ?
I was in the semifinal, celebratin' my wife's demise.
Big Chinese fella pulled me right over.
Look at that.
It was a bull shark.
He scraped me when I was takin' samples.
I got somethin' for ya. There's a thresher. See that, Chief?
Thresher's tail.
Thresher ?
It's a shark.
You want a drink ? Drink to your leg ?
I'll drink to your leg. Okay, we drink to our legs.
[ Hooper ] I got the creme de la creme.
Right here.
See that ?
[ Brody ] You're wearin' a sweater.
Right there. Mary Ellen Moffit.
She broke my heart. [ Laughing ]
What's that one ? [ Quint ] What ?
That one there on your arm.
Oh, a tattoo. I got that removed.
Don't tell me. Don't tell me. Mother.
What is it ?
Hooper, that's the USS Indianapolis.
- You were on the Indianapolis ?
- What happened ?
Japanese submarine slammed two torpedoes into her side.
Was comin' back from the island of Tinian Leyte.
Just delivered the bomb, the Hiroshima bomb.
Eleven hundred men went into the water.
Vessel went down in 1 2 minutes.
Didn't see the first shark for about half an hour.
Tiger, 1 3-footer. Know how you know that when you're in the water ?
You tell by lookin' from the dorsal to the tail.
What we didn't know
was our bomb mission had been so secret...
no distress signal had been sent.
They didn't even list us as overdue for a week.
Very first light, Chief, sharks come cruisin'.
We formed ourselves into tight groups.
Kinda like old squares in a battle, like you see on a calendar, like the Battle of Waterloo.
The idea was, shark comes to the nearest man,
that man starts poundin', hollerin', screamin'.
Sometimes the shark go away,
sometimes he wouldn't go away.
Sometimes that shark looks right into ya,
right into your eyes.
You know, a thing about a shark, he's got lifeless eyes.
Black eyes, like a doll's eyes.
When he comes at ya, doesn't seem to be livin',
until he bites ya and those black eyes roll over wide.
And then--
then you hear that terrible high-pitched screamin'.
The ocean turns red.
In spite of the pounding and hollering, they all come in.
They rip you to pieces.
You know, by the end of that first dawn,
lost a hundred men.
I don't know how many sharks, maybe a thousand.
I don't know how many men. They averaged six an hour.
On Thursday morning,
I bumped into a friend of mine, Robinson, from Cleveland,
baseball player, boatswain's mate.
I thought he was asleep.
Reached over to wake him up.
Bobbed up and down in the water like a top.
Upended.
Well, he'd been bitten in half below the waist.
Noon the fifth day, Mr. Hooper,
a Lockheed Ventura saw us. He swung in low and saw us.
Young pilot, a lot younger than Mr. Hooper.
He saw us and come in low. Three hours later,
a big fat PBY comes down and starts to pick us up.
That was the time I was most frightened,
waitin' for my turn.
I'll never put on a life jacket again.
Eleven hundred men went into the water.
31 6 men come out. The sharks took the rest.
June 29, 1 945.
Anyway,
we delivered the bomb.
What's that ?
It's a whale.
# Farewell and adieu #
# To you fair Spanish ladies #
# Farewell #
and adieu you ladies of Spain
# Show me the way to go home #
# I'm tired and I wanna go to bed #
# I had a little drink  #
about an hour ago
# And it's gone right to my head #
# Wherever I may roam #
# By land or sea or foam #
You will always hear me singin'this song [ Beeping ]
Show me the way to go home
# Boom, boom, boom Show me the way to go home #
# Boom, boom I'm tired and I wanna go to bed #
# I had a little drink about an hour ago # # And it went right to my head #
Wherever I may roam [ Banging ]
# On land or sea or foam #
# You can always hear me singing-- # [ Indistinct Noise ]
Start the engines.
[ Quint ] Fire her up ! Start the mill.
[ Hooper ] Busting shaft.
Chief, put out the fire, will ya ?
Pump her out. Done.
[ Quint ] Everybody on deck. [ Hooper ] He ate the light.
[ Brody ] Terrific. Excuse me.
[ Hooper ] Quint, what are you doing ? Don't waste your time.
[ Quint ] What's wrong with this shark ?
[ Quint ] Hooper, take the wheel.
Brody, forward deck. Watch for him.
You okay ?
Hey, Martin, you okay ?
[ Quint ] Hey, Chief, more left rudder. Pull your left hand down.
I can't. It'll only go about three inches.
[ Hooper ] Our injectors got scored from
the salt water in the fuel.
[ Quint ] The housing's bent. You can hear it.
Try the left rudder again, will ya ?
More left, good. Once again, now.
Quint, Quint, Quint ! There it is.
What do you say, Chief?
The barrel is up. It's right in the stern.
Think he's right under the keg. Grab the boat hook.
Quint, if we can get close enough,
I've got things on board that'll kill him.
Just want to goose him up. Come on.
Okay.
When he runs, drop that rope or you'll lose your hands.
I seen fingers torn out at the knuckles.
Whole sea's full of'em. Give it to me a minute.
[ Quint ] Haul in that line or it will foul us.
Start the engines.
- Where you goin' ? - I'm gonna make a phone call.
Hello ? Hello ?
Hello, Mayday ! Orca. Coast Guard ?
[ Brody ] Coast Guard, this is Orca. Do you read me ?
Coast Guard, this is Orca, do you--
Excuse me, Chief.
That's great ! That's just great !
Now where the hell are we, huh ?
You're certifiable, Quint, do you know that ?
You're certifiable ! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[ Hooper ] Boys. Oh, boys.
I think he's come back for his noon feeding.
Hook me up another barrel !
Take her around after him !
[ Quint ] Full throttle! Get me right up alongside him.
[ Hooper ] I can't! It's not gonna take it!
Five degrees port.
All right, hold your course.
Five degrees port now.
Hold your course.
Fast fish. [ Quint ] Watch my hand.
Be sure you watch my hand now. Follow me. Follow me.
All right, watch now. Starboard, starboard!
Run him down, Hooper.
Run him down ! Run him down !
Hard aport !
[ Quint ] Watch him ! Starboard! Starboard!
[ Brody ] I can't believe it! Two barrels and he's going down again.
He's incredible.
They're up again ! Now what ?
Why don't we lead the shark to shore instead
of him leading us to sea ?
Grab a couple of poles, okay ?
Hang on now, we're goin' around.
[ Quint ] Into starboard, easy.
I'm gonna back her up now. Watch those barrels, boys. Watch them !
All right, gentlemen, snag 'em.
Now then, tie them to the stern cleats.
Brody, bring your end around the cleat!
That's right. It'll lock itself off.
Give him room, Brody!
Aaah ! Stay clear of the line!
Watch it. Stand clear.
Stand away from those stern cleats !
Back home we got a taxidermy man.
He gonna have a heart attack when he see what I brung.
Throttle back ! You're losing your cleats !
[ Hooper ] Look at that mother. This one too. They're both going.
He's eating his way right through that line.
Yeah, he's working his way right up to us. Quint !
[ Hooper ] Come on, Quint!
Hurry! Quint!
Out of my way.
[ Quint ] Watch it!
Untie us ! He'll pull out the transom !
[ Quint ] Make it fast! We'll get another line in him.
I can't ! He's trying to run !
[ Quint ] He's gonna give us a ride!
[ Quint ] Pull, you son of a bitch.
Hope your back breaks ! Go on !
Pull your bloody heart out !
Tie him off ! Do it. Tie him off !
It's impossible ! It's impossible !
The line is too tight. He's towing us !
Cut him loose or he'll pull the transom off !
[ Hooper ] We're breaking up ! Cut it, man. It's coming off !
[ Hooper ] The ax! Get the ax!
We're breaking up ! We're breaking up !
Cut it ! Cut it ! Watch your hands!
Come on ! Hold it ! [ Hooper ] Cut it! I can't hold it!
Cut it! Cut it!
Can't stay down with three barrels on him.
Not with three barrels, he can't.
What about us ? Hooper,
get the pump out of the locker, will you ?
We're gonna sink, aren't we ?
Hooper, keep an eye on the barrels.
Pump it out, Chief.
Trying to go under !
He can't with three barrels on him.
You ever have one do this before ?
Hell, no.
[ Banging ] [ Quint ] Hold fast!
[ Hooper ] He's chasing us. I don't believe it.
I'm gonna draw him into the shallows.
Draw him into shallow water, draw him in and drown him.
We're headin' in, Brody. Thank Christ.
Have you ever had a great white do this ? No !
How far do we have to go ?
Quint, don't put that much pressure on them.
Quint, goddamn it ! Shut up ! Get back there !
I'll break the engine-- It's gonna tear up--
Hold on, Martin.
# Farewell and adieu #
# You fair Spanish ladies #
You ladies of Spain
For we received orders For to sail back to Boston
You idiot, you burned out the bearings.
[ Brody ] All right, stop the boat. Stop the boat ! Stop it !
Hooper !
Chief.
Hooper, what exactly can you do with these things of yours ?
Well, I think I can pump 20 ccs of strychnine nitrate into him,
if I can get close enough.
Can you get this little needle through his skin ?
No, I can't do that.
But if I can get him close enough to this cage, I could get him in the mouth.
That shark will rip that cage -- You got any better suggestions ?
Easy, easy.
All right, up she goes.
Ease her up.
I ain't got no spit.
Try and keep him off me until I'm lower.
Okay, okay, I'm ready.
Bring him up, goddamn it !
Bring him up now !
Pull it up ! Pull it !
Bring him up. What are you waiting for?
Come on, Quint, bring him in.
It's giving way !
Rig something. Rig something!
Got it ? All right.
It's coming. Slower.
Slower!
Come on, show me the tank. Blow up !
Blow up !
Smile, you son-of-a-bitch !
Quint ? No.
Can we get in on those ?
Hey, what day is this ?
It's Wednesday -- it's Tuesday, I think.
I think the tide's with us.
Keep kickin'.
I used to hate the water.
I can't imagine why.